Juan Camilo Arévalo Arboleda

Ph.D. candidate in Computer Science and Engineering

arevaloarboled@gmail.com

% arevaloarboled.github.io



in ArevaloCamilo





Summary

Computer scientist with expertise in audio processing, audio spatialization, extended reality (XR) development, interactive systems, machine learning, and web development. Experience in international and interdisciplinary research groups. Stands out for excellent performance in programming code and versatility between programming languages and

Interests: Research, machine learning, web development, and XR development.



Experience

Teaching Assistant

University of Aizu

■ Currently −04/2019

- Aizuwakamatsu, Japan
- Assist lectures and exercises of virtual reality, sound and audio processing, C++ programming, computer graphics, software exercise, introduction to data management, introduction to multimedia, and introduction to programming.
- Tasks: Prepare material for lectures, grade undergraduate courses exercises/quizzes, and solve student doubts regarding the course contents.

Research Assistant

Pontifical Javeriana University Cali

12/2018 -06/2018

- Cali, Colombia
- Built an online game "Tramas: parques intercultural," as a didactic tool to promote the intercultural dialogue.
- · Perform user validations.
- Server deploy and administration.

Internship

University Complutense of Madrid

11/2018

- Madrid, Spain
- Researched and implemented a tracking map for artwork of artistic heritage value during the Spanish civil war and postwar.
- Server administration (pgp.ucm.es).

Research Assistant

Pontifical Javeriana University Cali

12/2014 -08/2014

- Cali, Colombia
- Researched, designed, and implemented an algorithm capable of finding salsa song choruses for the construction of a data set.

Education

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering University of Aizu

(expected graduation) 03/2024 -04/2021

Aizuwakamatsu, Japan

Research topic: Audio spatialization, all grades A.

M.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering University of Aizu

■ 03/2021 −04/2019

Aizuwakamatsu, Japan

Research topic: Audio spatialization, all grades A.

B.Sc. in Computer Science

Pontifical Javeriana University Cali

11/2018 -07/2012

GPA: 3.81/5.0. Program with ABET international accreditation.

Achievements

Outstanding student research assistantship Granted by the University of Aizu for the period 04/2022-03/2023 due to the performance during the first year of the doctoral program.

Q 3rd prize in AES student competition: MAT-LAB plugin 2021

International competition to design an audio production VST plugin using MATLAB.

- Q Cum Laude baccalaureate in computer sciences Granted by the Pontifical Javeriana University Cali.
- 2 3rd prize in Expo poster REDIS South West Node 2018

Research graduation contest held by 21 undergraduate Computer Science programs institutions in Colombia.

Ranked 8th in the ACM ICPC South America / North Regional 2016

Member of "PUJC-CodeBreakers" team from 2013 to 2016 (best rank at 2016).

Publications

Search author as Camilo Arevalo or with the OR-CID 0000-0002-3505-2092 in Google scholar or Research Gate. 3 journals and 9 conference papers. Relevant papers:

- Virtual Reality Tool for Exploration of Three-Dimensional Cellular Automata.
- Usability and Narrative Geologation for the Monitoring of Spanish Artistic Heritage.
- Real-time Spatialization via Eigen Decomposition of Head-related Transfer Functions.



Lisp

Ruby

Spanish

English

Skills

</>> Programming

C/C++/C# (6 years) Python (6 years) **JavaScript** (4 years) PHP (4 years) (4 years) R SQL (4 years) (2 years) Java (2 years)

A Languages

(2 years)

(Native)

X Frameworks &

Matlab	(5	years)
Unity	(5	years)
AngularJS	(3	years)
Arduino	(3	years)
Boostrap	(3	years)
MySql	(3	years)
NodeJS	(3	years)
OpenMP/MPI	(3	years)
Pure Data	(3	years)
Keras	(2	years)
OpenCV	(2	years)
Docker	(2	years)

(Fluent) Japanese(Intermediate) React (2 years)

February 18, 2023